<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network Namespaces on Rootless Containers</title>
    <link>https://rootlesscontaine.rs/how-it-works/netns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network Namespaces on Rootless Containers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rootlesscontaine.rs/how-it-works/netns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Outgoing connections</title>
      <link>https://rootlesscontaine.rs/how-it-works/netns/outgoing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootlesscontaine.rs/how-it-works/netns/outgoing/</guid>
      <description>Unsharing network namespaces isn&amp;rsquo;t only for assigning IP addresses; it is also essential to protect abstract UNIX sockets on the host from containerized processes.
However, unsharing network namespaces for Rootless Containers isn&amp;rsquo;t straightforward, because vEth pairs cannot be created across UserNS boundaries without the privilege.
LXC uses a SETUID binary called lxc-user-nic for setting up vEth pairs.
Other implementations including Docker/Moby and Podman typically use TAP devices instead of vEth pairs, and run a usermode network stack called slirp, which translates Ethernet packets to unprivileged socket system calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incoming connections</title>
      <link>https://rootlesscontaine.rs/how-it-works/netns/incoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootlesscontaine.rs/how-it-works/netns/incoming/</guid>
      <description>Connections incoming from the Internet cannot directly reach network namespaces.
Two forwarder implementations are used for transferring connections to Rootless Containers&#39; network namespaces.
RootlessKit The RootlessKit implementation is used by both Docker/Moby and Podman.
slirp4netns slirp4netns also has its own port forwarder.
The slirp4netns implementation is slower than RootlessKit, however, the slirp4netns implementation can keep source IP addresses, while the RootlessKit implementation treats all connections as if they were from 127.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
